# Alessio Mancinelli

Paciano, Umbria, Italy

📱 +39 3425034063 | 🗷 alessiomancinellil97@outlook.it | 💣 raiseku.github.io | 🖸 github.com/Raiseku | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/alessiomancinellil97

## Personal Profile

A knowledge-hungry & music-lover young guy. Zealous about software engineering and with 2+ years of experience specialising in machine learning, python development and full-stack development. I also try to be a youtuber, freelancer, gamer and guitarist. Always focused on building awesome projects that can enrich my knowledge. Primarily, looking for Machine Learning / Data Engineer / Python Developer roles.

## **Education**

#### **Mathematics and Computer Science Department**

Perugia, IT

MSc in Computer Science - Intelligent and Mobile Computing

Sept 2019 - July 2021

- 110/110 summa cum laude
- Thesis: An Argumentative Explanation of Machine Learning Outcomes.
- Themese: Explainable Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Argumentation Framework, Knowledge Representation

#### **Mathematics and Computer Science Department**

Perugia, IT

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Sept 2016 - Sept 2019

- 108/110
- Thesis: Student Behaviour Models for a University LMS.
- Themese: Machine Learning, Behaviour Models, Data Analysis

#### Istituto Omnicomprensivo Rosselli Rasetti

Castiglione del lago, IT

Scientific Diploma - Information Technology and Telecommunications

Sept 2011 - July 2016

- 100/100
- Thesis: Artificial Intelligence

## Work Experience

#### Micra Software & Services - R&D Team

Corciano, IT

Software Developer

Researcher

Programmer

Sept 2021 - Current

- Collaborated with a four-person team to develop Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing models for solving real-world problems related to the legal field. Each model has an associated web interface based on Angular or JSF.
- Responsable for the innovation of existing products by integrating conversational Chatbots and custom made Name Entity Recognition Systems
  based on Spacy library and TINT.
- Tutor of PCTO students and interns; building of training courses on a github repository inside which there were lessons, tasks and projects to be completed.
- Technical Skills: Python, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Keras, Machine Learning, NLP, Java, HTML/CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, Angular, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills, Report Writing.

Fiverr Italy

Freelancer

Sept 2021 - Current

I'm offering my programming skills as a Freelancer to make Machine Learning based applications and Telegram Chatbots.

- This offering try programming skills as a Freelancer to make machine Learning based applications and releg
   Communication with the client to establish the work to be done, time required and available budget.
- **Technical Skills:** Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Sqlite, Git, Telethon, Chatbot, Machine Learning.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking, Problem Solving.

#### **Mathematics and Computer Science Department**

Perugia, IT

• Research on applications and state of the art of Explainable Artificial Intelligence; use of existing products and study of possible insights.

- In-depth study of Explainable By Design models such as Decision Trees and Rule-based Classifiers. Application of LIME to Neural Networks and Random Forest models.
- Confirmation that is possible to provide an explanation via Argumentation Framework.
- Technical Skills: Python, Explainable Artificial Intelligence, LIME, Watson, Spacy, Knowledge Representation.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Communication, Problem Solving, Decision making.

#### **Mathematics and Computer Science Department**

Perugia, IT

Dec 2017 - March 2018

• Creation of a Plug-in for the E-Learning platform Moodle used by the University of Perugia.

- The plugin was similar to the popular *Kahoot* game, which allowed students to learn something new through gamification.
- Technical Skills: HTML/CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Decision making, Presentation skills, Report Writing.

Gen 2021 - April 2021

isights.

## **Publications**

#### An Argumentative Explanation of Machine Learning Outcomes - PDF

Stefano Bistarelli, Alessio Mancinelli, Francesco Santini, Carlo Taticchi

Computational Models of Argument - Proceedings of COMMA 2022

#### Hate Speech and Stereotypes with Artificial Neural Networks - PDF

Giulio Biondi, Valentina Franzoni, Alessio Mancinelli, Alfredo Milani

Computational Science and Its Applications - ICCSA 2022 Workshops

**Behaviour Models for a University LMS - PDF**Giulio Biondi, Valentina Franzoni, Alessio Mancinelli, Alfredo Milani

Computational Science and Its Applications - ICCSA 2022 Workshops

**Projects** 

### **Gender Prediction - Binary Classification**

Mathematics and Computer Science Department

· Analysing written text from five different sources and discover patterns in relation to the two available classes.

- · Apply feature engineering on text to create a dataset that will be used as input of a custom made Neural Network.
- Technical Skills: Python, NLTK, Scikit-learn, Keras, Word Embedding, Neural Network, Word2Vec.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Presentation skills, Report writing.

Booking Manager Exam project

Cardiff, Wales

Malaga, Spain

Malaga, Spain

23 July 2022

Exam project

30 Sept 2022

Mathematics and Computer Science Department

- Creation of a site based on AngularJS for reservations management.
- Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript, AngularJs, MySQL.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Report writing, Leadership, Teamwork, Problem solving.

Orders Management Bot Freetime project

Fiverr

- Telegram Bot written in python that's able to manage a set of orders inside a local database.
- Technical Skills: Python, Sqlite, Theleton, SQL.
- Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Communication, Time management.

Skills

**Programming** Python (Pandas, Keras, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Telethon, PyMongo), Java, PHP, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

**Miscellaneous** Explainable Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Angular, Latex (Overleaf), Git.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation, Report Writing, Critical thinking.

Interests\_

**Cooking** I love cooking. I can make most Italian-style dishes and my own pasta.

Video Games I always had the competitive gaming gene. I mostly play on my computer and my favorite genre is FPS.

**Gym** I have my morning routine where i walk in the fresh air and do exercises.

Music I started playing guitar when I was 15. I love going to concerts and listening to music while I'm coding.

**Youtube Videos** I opened a youtube channel where i create programming video tutorials for my little community.

**Personal Finance** I like to keep track of my income and expenses. I tend to be a frugal person and an investor.

Languages.

**Italian** Mother tongue

**English** Professional proficiency

I give consent to process my data with the purpose of the recruitment process, in accordance to the Regulation of the European Parliament 679/2016, regarding the protection of natural persons and free movement of such data.